(E)	ashtimus@gmail.com
T)	t.me/ashtimus
(L) ————	linkedin.com/in/aleksandr-kholopov/

ALEKS KHOLOPOV

Product designer currently based in Saint-Petersburg, Russia.

Designing systems, apps, websites and digital illustrations. Specializing in data visualization, web and UX/UI design using Figma. Passionate about simplicity, I'm constantly trying to build clean and simple products to make people's lives easier.

With more than 15 years in the industry, started out in the advertising sphere, moved on to digital production, and currently working at lTigris to establish the future of optical stores worldwide.

Available for new projects and / or relocation.

PROFESSIONAL
EXPERTISE

AKH.DIGITAL -

- UX Design
- Wireframe and Interactive prototyping
- Knowledge of methods and techniques in visual UI design in the context of both web and mobile applications
- Design systems and styleguides
- Graphic design + digital illustration
- Branding, Logo & Identity Design

TOOLKIT

- Figma, Zeplin
- Adobe CC (Photoshop, InDesign, Illustrator)
- Slack, Miro, Atlassian Jira, YouTrack, Github
- VSC, Atom/Typora, Notion
- UI frameworks Element UI, Ant Design, Apex Charts, Ant Charts

LANGUAGES

- Russian native
- English fluent
- German basic skills
 - + skills in linguistics and translation
 - + technical writing & editing

DEV

understanding CSS / HTML / JS

(E)	 ashtimus@gmail.com
(T)	 t.me/ashtimus
(L)	 linkedin.com/in/aleksandr-kholopov/

EXPERIENCE

AKH.DIGITAL -

Lead UI Designer & UX Researcher @ ITigris

2019 - Present

UI / UX Designer @ Siemens AG

2018

Senior UI / UX & Digital Designer @ TASSTA GmbH

2015 - 2019

UI / UX Designer @ Saprun Group

2015

Graphic Designer @ St. Petersburg International

Economic Forum

2015

Graphic Designer @ Finch Industrial Tools Russia

2006 - 2015

EDUCATION

Post-Graduate Course @ Institute of Management and Economics

Economics and Management in the National

Economy

2004 - 2006

Master's degree @ Moscow Open Social University

Linguistics and Cross-Culture Communication

2003 - 2004

Bachelor's degree @ Institute of Management and Economics

Linguistics and Cross-Culture Communication

1999 - 2003